[Music]
foreign
automation Advanced Training
so this is our
lesson one
in terms of advanced concepts trainings
are it's a lesson 16 in terms of overall
triceps automation Concepts
okay so in this lesson I'm gonna teach
you how can we use and how can we create
business parameters in present testoster
by using latest task 16 version
please do subscribe to the channel click
on Bell icon you'll receive
notifications whenever I publish more
videos thank you
okay so what are business parameters and
how can we use them and why do these
business parameters useful for us let us
understand first
so if you remember in my previous
session I have already teached you about
creating libraries and then creating
reusable tested blogs in the library
right so to create you different test
cases right you'll be using
a series of steps same kind of series of
tips right so those reusable test steps
you can store in the libraries okay so
by using those libraries you can easily
create multiple test cases so whatever
the reusable desktops you can just drag
and drop into your test case and then
modify the test case accordingly right
so now any modifications made
in the reusable test blocks of the
library will also apply to those test
cases which are created with the
reference of these reusable tester
blocks correct so that's why
cannot make any changes to your library
let's assume if a user wants to create
multiple test cases
with different test days or test data
sets
by using libraries is it possible no
so if you modify
any reference test case or if you modify
any tester block then the corresponding
test cases all the test cases whatever
referencing your library will get
modified so since user data varies for
different test cases it would become a
problem if we attempt to use testless
test step libraries with the same data
so what is the solution
the solution is business parameters
so there is a solution that allows each
tester to use their own user data for
different test cases
that you are referring from your library
reusable tester blocks
so you can use your libraries you can
use your reusable tested blocks and then
you can create test cases but you can
change your test data by using business
parameters it's very very important
Concepts so by end of this lesson you
will be able to create and use business
business parameters at test case levels
so if you remember in my previous
session I have
teached you about test case
configurations parameters test case
configuration parameters so those test
case configuration parameters are at
test case level
these business parameters are a test
case level but you can change these
business parameters for each and every
test case basically you can use
different test data sets while creating
test cases from your libraries okay so
now let's jump onto the system and see
and understand how can we create and how
can we use these business parameters
so this is my Tasker 16 latest version
so if you remember in my previous
sessions right I have explained you
how to create library and the reusable
tested blogs within the library right
and these reusable tester blocks we have
used
create
the new test cases
so if you see here
if the folders are representing a
reference here reference that means
these test cases are created by using
your reusable tested blocks right if you
remember this process folder there is a
modification that's why what we did we
resolved the reference and modified
steps right but here in today's session
what if I want to create a new test case
but I don't want to use a same set of
test data right so then you can let's
say I want to use my own URL if I want
to use my own email and password while
creating
my test cases from reusable test blocks
so you cannot change
so if you change your email ID and
password Here
your actual precondition test blocks
also Gonna Change
right if you make a change here
in the test case your entire library is
going to change
so that means if you change the library
all the test cases referenced to these
reusable blocks will change
right so now
I want to use the reusable test blocks
to create a new test case to automate a
new test case but I don't want to use
the same test data in all the test cases
how can we do that okay so let's copy
this
the previous test case that we have
created in my previous session
and then
paste this
paste it here
foreign
and rename this as
business
parameters okay
done
so now this is my new test case
so before you start working on this
first I want to make changes to my
library
okay under Library go to precondition
so for this precondition
I want to create business parameters
here why I want to create two sorry
three business parameters right click
you have to click on create whenever you
have to create business parameter at
folder level right click on this click
on business parameter
so once we create business parameter
here right now you can start creating
actual
business I mean sorry for this business
promoter you can create parameters one
two
three
so let's name this as the first one
URL is my first business parameter
username is my second business parameter
and then
password is my third business parameter
okay so now let's expand this let's
expand this
so now if you want to
replace the hard-coded values right here
in the precondition
just remove this these hard coded let's
say I want to remove this URL
I want to remove the value of username
I want to remove the value of password
right so simply what you need to do is
have to
drag and drop
one minute what you need to do you need
to drag and drop your business
parameters okay so here
for example URL right drag and drop here
so
so drag this business parameter drop
here what it will do it's going to
create so before that sorry before you
drop actually I have to remove the
values okay remove the value
drag and drop URL
so what it will do is going to create a
link to this parameter business
parameter
open curly braces PL
open Square basis your parameter name
close Square braces and close curly
braces
in the same way
for this email
remove this email
remove the password
simply drag and drop your username and
password here okay
so let me
sorry
password
okay now I want to use this username
right
drag
and drop here
in the same way password
drag
and drop onto password
okay
so it's created your so let me just one
more time I want to drag and drop my
password okay
because it's a password it's going to
show it as
a password field drag and drop it to the
password
that's it so now that means now it's
created the links
of your business parameters to the
values
right so now let's go back to your test
case here now
here if you see expand your precondition
okay in this case
here now I can pass the business
parameters here
right so let's pass the business
parameters to this test case
let's say I want to use this URL for
this test case okay I can use this URL
and I want to you whose password has
username as this one and the password
as
this
right
okay let me change my username okay
this is my username and this is my
password let's say if tomorrow I want to
create one more you test case you can
simply copy this and paste it here now
this time you can change your business
business parameters new URL you can
provide new username new password
so
this test case will run
with this kind of test data set another
test case will run with another test
data set so basically you can create
multiple test cases but you can execute
the test cases with different data sets
so now let's just simply run this test
case right click
so before run let me close the web
okay so right click here now and run
this
in the scratchbook
so it opens your this thing
it should say it took the URL from the
business parameter and then username
password from the business parameter
that's it
is going to execute your entire test
case
so basically this time we have taken
the test data from the business
parameter
and if you want to create another test
case with the different data set
you can simply copy and paste
and you can chain the business parameter
values
okay
okay so let's close this okay that's
done
so let's go back here let's say I want
to copy this again okay I want to create
one more but I want to use some other
test data set now okay right click and
paste
so here in this right in this test case
now I can change the data set here I can
change my username as something else
and I can change the password to
something else correct
and now you can run this that means two
test cases we can run with different
data sets
so this way hey you need not to
so you are not what what is the purpose
of business parameter is you can reuse
your test step blocks
automate new test cases but you need not
to use the same test data that is
available your in your
reasonable tested blocks you can change
your test data
and you can use your own test data for
each test case that you automate
okay hope you all understand the very
important concept of business parameters
okay if you have any queries leave your
queries in the comment box I'll try to
respond to your queries
thank you hope you all understand the
concepts of business parameters and why
do we use business parameters and how
can you use these business parameters by
using latest version price and testoster
16.
please do subscribe to the channel click
on Bell icon you'll receive
notifications whenever I publish more
videos thank you
[Music]